In this lecture, we want to look at another architectural consideration that you should
think about while building rack-based applications.
There are two ways through which you can do the optimization.
One is using the re-ranker model and metadata filtering.
So now let's go ahead and take a look at both.
So re-ranker models are used to improve the relevance of the retrieved results for any query.
So re-ranker model calculates the relevance of chunks to the query and re-orders the results
based on the scores that it calculates.
So now if you take a look at the architecture, so once the user has posed the question,
it passes through the text emitting model, you create an embedding, then do a similarity search,
and then through a similarity search, you get some context chunks.
This is where re-ranker model comes into play and it re-orders the chunks based on relevance.
So here are a couple of re-ranking models, so you have one from Amazon re-rank 1.0,
and this is the model ID, and then there is one from Kohir re-rank 3.5, and here is the model ID.
Now let's quickly understand through an example how it exactly works.
Now let's say you have built an e-commerce chatbot, and the customer is asking,
what is the enterprise refund policy?
So how the process work?
So the first step is retriever fetches the chunks, and vector search could return up to
20 to 25 chunks, and you can see here.
So once we have the user query, the initial retrieval will retrieve about 25 chunks or so,
then next, so then the re-ranker model scores each pair for true relevance.
So each query that has been retrieved, it will provide it a relevance score based on the
query and the retrieved chunk.
Then the results are re-ordered, maybe only 5 to 8 most relevant chunks remain.
So you can see here there were 25 initial chunks that were retrieved,
then the re-ranker model re-orders and selects only top 5 or so chunks.
And then these are sent to the LLM, so the model sees a cleaner, more accurate context,
and generates better results.
So what are the benefits of using a re-ranker model?
First, it improves answer accuracy by selecting the most relevant context.
Then it reduces hallucinations by removing weak or irrelevant chunks, and then finally,
it lowers token usage by sending fewer higher quality chunks to the LLM.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.